# Guy Prochilo

### About

I am a lecturer of research methods in psychology at ISN Psychology and a researcher in the Cognitive Behaviour Therapy Research Unit at ISN Innovations (Melbourne, Australia). My current research focuses on evaluating the effectiveness of electronic health (eHealth) interventions for reducing psychological stress and improving wellbeing using randomized controlled trial methodologies.

### Contact

Email: gprochilo@isn.edu.au ORCHID: 0000-0002-1544-3694
Website: guyprochilo.com Google Scholar: Guy A. Prochilo
Twitter: twitter.com/@GuyProchilo Publons: Guy A. Prochilo

#### Education

2020	Ph.D. (Psychology)	University of Melbourne
	• Thesis: Organizatio Management	nal Neuroscience with Applications to Stress
2013	B.Sc. (Hons)	University of Queensland
2012	B.Sc. & B.Bus.Man.	University of Queensland

# **Employment**

2020 - date	Lecturer & Unit Coordinator, ISN Psychology, Melbourne, Australia • Research Methods (Bachelor of Psychological Science Hons)
	<ul> <li>Advanced Research Methods (Master of Clinical Psychology)</li> <li>Research Project A (Master of Professional Psychology)</li> </ul>
2020 - date	Researcher, ISN Innovations, Melbourne, Australia
2019 - 2020	Statistical Consultant, ISN Psychology, Melbourne, Australia
2019 - 2020	R Statistical Software Volunteer Trainer, Researcher Community Training Service, University of Melbourne, Melbourne, Australia
2013	Research Methods Tutor, UQ Business School, University of Queensland, Brisbane, Australia
2012	Research Intern, School of Psychology, University of Queensland, Brisbane, Australia (Supervisor: Dr. Hannes Zacher)

# **Publications**

2021	Prochilo, G. A., Costa, R. J. S., Hassed, C., Chambers, R., &
	Molenberghs, P. (2021). A 16-week aerobic exercise and mindfulness-
	based intervention on chronic psychosocial stress: A pilot and
	feasibility study. Pilot and Feasibility Studies, 7(1), 64.
	https://doi.org/10.1186/s40814-020-00751-6
2019	Prochilo, G. A., Louis, W. R., Bode, S., Zacher, H., & Molenberghs,
	P. (2019). An Extended Commentary on Post-publication Peer
	Review in Organizational Neuroscience. $Meta ext{-}Psychology, 3.$
	https://doi.org/10.15626/MP.2018.935
2017	Molenberghs, P., <b>Prochilo, G.,</b> Steffens, N. K., Zacher, H., &
	Haslam, S. A. (2017). The Neuroscience of Inspirational Leadership:
	The Importance of Collective-Oriented Language and Shared Group

Membership. Journal of Management, 43(7), 2168–2194.

https://doi.org/10.1177/0149206314565242

# Presentations

2020	Prochilo, G. A. Three ways you can get started with open science right now. ISN Psychology, Melbourne, Australia. Invited Presentation. Download.
2019	Prochilo, G. A., Louis, W., Bode, S., Zacher, H., & Molenberghs, P. Organizational Neuroscience Needs Careful and Consistent Postpublication Peer Review. Association for Interdisciplinary Metaresearch & Open Science Conference, Melbourne, Australia.
2018	Prochilo, G. A., Dominguez, J., Costa, R., & Molenberghs, P. The Effects of a 16-week Combined Aerobic Exercise and Mindfulness-based Intervention: A Pilot Study. Society for Neuroscience Annual Meeting, San Diego, United States.
2018	Prochilo, G. A., Dominguez, J., Costa, R., & Molenberghs, P. The Effects of a 16-week Combined Aerobic Exercise and Mindfulness-based Intervention: A Pilot Study. Australasian Society for Social and Affective Neuroscience Annual Meeting, Brisbane, Australia.
2016	Prochilo, G. A., Molenberghs, P., Steffens, NK., Zacher, H., & Haslam, SA. The Neuroscience of Inspirational Leadership: The Importance of Collective-oriented Language and Shared Group

Membership. Australasian Society for Social and Affective

Neuroscience Annual Meeting, Sydney, Australia.

#### **Collaborators**

- Associate Professor Pascal Molenberghs, ISN Psychology, Melbourne, Australia
- Professor Hannes Zacher, University of Leipzig, Leipzig, Germany
- Dr. Ricardo Da Costa, Monash University, Melbourne, Australia
- Associate Professor Stefan Bode, University of Melbourne, Melbourne, Australia
- Professor Winnifred Louis, University of Queensland, Brisbane, Australia
- Dr Juan Dominguez, Australian Catholic University, Melbourne, Australia
- Associate Professor Craig Hassed, Monash University, Melbourne, Australia
- Dr. Richard Chambers, Monash University, Melbourne, Australia

### **Current Supervision**

2021 - date

Group Project: A randomized pretest-posttest waitlist-controlled trial to examine the effects of an online mindfulness-based intervention on psychological stress and wellbeing in tertiary education students.

- Honours Students: (1) Carmen Phung Tong, (2) Niva Perera, (3) Dana Najmeddine, (4) Asad Khan, (5) Azra Mehmeti
- Master's Students: (6) Zoe Lazaridis

2021 - date

Group Project: Can smartphone apps be used to reduce psychological stress in people who are currently experiencing psychological stress: a randomized controlled trial?

- Honours Students: (1) Puya Pazir, (2) Angus Panther, (3) Tarshi Barua.
- Master's Students: (4) Oscar Goldberg

# Completed Supervision

2020

Group Project: The effects of an online mindfulness-based intervention on psychological stress: a randomized pretest-posttest waitlist-controlled pilot and feasibility study.

• Honours Students: (1) Ciaran Barton, (2) Kathryn Cianciarulo, (3) Eman Shehata, (4) Esma Voloder, (5) Caroline D'Souza, (6) Daniel Abela, (7) Lillian Underhill, (8) Carolina Debek, (9) Khadijah Duarte, (10) Mona Andalib.

#### Journal Reviewer

BMC Medical Education

### Awards

2019	Conference Poster Award (Top 10). Melbourne Research Bazaar
	Conference. Researcher Community Training Service, University of
	Melbourne, Melbourne, Australia
2018	Melbourne Research Scholarship, University of Melbourne,
	Melbourne, Australia.
2017	Monash University Volunteer of the Year Award
	(Nominated). Monash University, Melbourne, Australia.

# **Professional Memberships**

- Association for Interdisciplinary Meta-Research and Open Science, aimos.community
- Australia and New Zealand Open Research Network, anzopenresearch.org
- Society for the Improvement of Psychological Science, improving psych.org
- The Australasian Society for Social and Affective Neuroscience, as4san.com